<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

	<properties>
		<title>Usage</title>
		<author email="ludwig@puresol-technologies.com">Rick-Rainer Ludwig</author>
	</properties>

	<!-- Optional HEAD element, which is copied as is into the XHTML <head> 
		element -->
	<!-- head> <meta . /> </head -->

	<body>
		<section name="Building from Source">
			<p>
				After retrieving the source code the build can be done with Maven
				as easy
				as calling:
			</p>
			<tt>mvn install</tt>
			<p>
				After the build has finished successfully, the KickStar executable
				jar can be found in
				<tt>target</tt>
				directory.
			</p>
		</section>
		<section name="Installation">
			<p>
				The Installation can be done anywhere wanted. On Unix like System an
				installation directory like
				<tt>/opt/JavaApp</tt>
				is suitable. Within this directory place the
				<tt>kickstart.jar</tt>
				and the
				<tt>KickStart.properties</tt>
				file (beware of small and capital letters in Unix OS). Additionally,
				some directories need to be added to place the
				actual libraries into
				it. A recommendation is to create the
				following
				sub-directories:
			</p>
			<ul>
				<li>
					<b>bin:</b>
					Within this directory all executable scripts are located which
					actually start KickStart and choose the Class in which the needed
					main() method can be found for startup.
				</li>
				<li>
					<b>config:</b>
					This directory should be treated as class library directory and
					is
					used for configuration files which are placed into the CLASSPATH
					and loaded as resource.
				</li>
				<li>
					<b>extlib:</b>
					To
					<tt>extlib</tt>
					all libraries from external vendors should go
					in.
				</li>
				<li>
					<b>lib:</b>
					Should be the directory where all classes go in which are from
					own
					developments and which are changed during development cycles.
				</li>
				<li>
					<b>log:</b>
					Within this directory all log files which are generated by the
					tools should be located. KickStart itself does not generate any log
					files.
				</li>
			</ul>
			<p>
				All directory naming is meant to be inside the installation
				directory
				of the KickStart framework.
			</p>
		</section>
		<section name="Starting an Application">
			<p>
				After a successful installation of KickStart and the needed
				libraries,
				KickStart can be started a normal JRE as easy as:
			</p>
			<tt>
				java -jar kickstart-1.0.0.jar MainClassName parameter1 parameter2
				...
			</tt>
			<p>
				The version information needs to be adapted.
				<tt>MainClassName</tt>
				is to be replaced with the actual main class containing the main
				method for startup. The parameters for the application follow
				afterwards as usual.
			</p>
		</section>
		<section name="Additional System Configuration">
			<p>
				In the next sections some information is given beyond the normal
				KickStart setup to include the Java application more deeply into the
				OS.
			</p>
			<subsection name="PATH Variable">
				<p>
					On Unix one adds KickStart to a global
					<tt>PATH</tt>
					variable by
					changing
					<tt>/etc/profile</tt>
					,
					<tt>/etc/profile</tt>
					,
					<tt>/etc/bash.bashrc</tt>
					or
					<tt>/etc/bash.bashrc.local</tt>
					. The
					location depends on the System used. For user related changes
					the
					files
					<tt>~/.profile</tt>
					or
					<tt>~/.bashrc</tt>
					should be checked.
				</p>
				<p>For Windows in the System Control Panel the path can be adjusted.
				</p>
			</subsection>

			<subsection name="Usage in Cron">
				<p>
					To add the KickStart
					<tt>bin</tt>
					directory into the Cron PATH
					variable modify
					<tt>/etc/crontab</tt>
					and add a line like
					<tt>PATH=/usr/bin:/usr/sbin:/sbin:/bin:/usr/lib/news/bin</tt>
					.
				</p>
			</subsection>
		</section>
	</body>
</document>                                              
